<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Featured on Andrew Bancroft</title>
    <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/categories/featured/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Featured on Andrew Bancroft</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 18:23:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/categories/featured/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Xcode Project Dependencies with CocoaPods</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2016/02/03/managing-xcode-project-dependencies-with-cocoapods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 18:23:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2016/02/03/managing-xcode-project-dependencies-with-cocoapods/</guid>
      <description>Announcing &amp;#8211; New Pluralsight Course! I&amp;#8217;m excited to announce the publication of my new course for Pluralsight titled &amp;#8220;Managing Xcode Project Dependencies with CocoaPods&amp;#8221;!
Not a Pluralsight subscriber? I would wholeheartedly recommend checking out their plans. They&amp;#8217;ve even got a free trial! Being a Pluralsight subscriber has literally been the single most impactful influence on my growth as a developer apart from at-the-keyboard experience.
Our team at work uses Pluralsight as a major portion of our developer training efforts, so there&amp;#8217;s an idea to pitch to your boss if you don&amp;#8217;t want to purchase an individual subscription!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swift Unit Testing – Verifying Method Calls</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2014/12/22/swift-unit-testing-verifying-method-calls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 13:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2014/12/22/swift-unit-testing-verifying-method-calls/</guid>
      <description>In this unit testing screencast for Swift developers, we explore how to use Test Driven Development to verify method calls.
Getting Started Guide If you&amp;#8217;re new to unit testing or are trying to get set up with unit testing in a Swift project, you might check out my getting started guide before jumping into the screencast.
Screencast Large / Full-Screen Viewing
GitHub Example GitHub repo of the example developed in the screencast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swift Unit Testing Resources</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2014/12/19/swift-unit-testing-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 12:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2014/12/19/swift-unit-testing-resources/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;#8217;ve researched Test Driven Development practices in general, and for iOS / Mac applications, I&amp;#8217;ve been helped by several sources. I&amp;#8217;ve also discovered a few things the hard way, so I&amp;#8217;m combining and maintaining this list of resources to help point you in some helpful directions as you adventure in unit testing your iOS apps.
Jump to&amp;#8230;   Pluralsight courses   Blogs   User group talks   At andrewcbancroft.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>