<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WWDC on Andrew Bancroft</title>
    <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/categories/wwdc/</link>
    <description>Recent content about iOS development with Swift in WWDC  from Andrew Bancroft.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/categories/wwdc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Download macOS Beta Installer</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/blog/musings/download-macos-beta-installer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/blog/musings/download-macos-beta-installer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you log into the Apple Developer portal, you can easily download a restore image (ipsw file) for beta versions of macOS, but it’s not helpful if you want to install macOS on a separate volume on your existing Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual macOS installer is much more useful. The only issue is that it’s not exactly intuitive to download.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how to do it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-turn-on-beta-updates&#34;&gt;Step 1: Turn on Beta Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the Settings app on your mac&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click General&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click Software Update&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn on Beta Updates for macOS Sequoia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2-use-terminal-to-download-the-installer&#34;&gt;Step 2: Use Terminal to download the installer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open a terminal window&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;softwareupdate --download --fetch-full-installer --full-installer-version 15.0&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you run that command, you&amp;rsquo;ll see a message in the console:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scanning for 15.0 installer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you skipped Step 1 and didn&amp;rsquo;t already opt in to receiving beta updates from Apple, you may get an error message:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install failed with error: Update not found&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve got Beta updates turned on though, you should see the softwareupdate utility begin to download the installer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry if you see the words &amp;ldquo;Installing xx%&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s not actually going to update your primary operating system.
It&amp;rsquo;s actually just downloading the installer to your Applications folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-find-the-installer-in-your-applications-folder&#34;&gt;Step 3: Find the installer in your Applications folder&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Finder and navigate to your Applications folder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should be able to find the &lt;code&gt;Install macOS 15 beta&lt;/code&gt; application if the download was successful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve got the installer, you can install macOS on a separate volume on the same Mac that you’re running the currently-released version of macOS!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WWDC - The Worldwide Developer Community</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/blog/musings/wwdc-worldwide-developer-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/blog/musings/wwdc-worldwide-developer-community/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;June is an invigorating time for iOS developers worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invigorating&amp;hellip;  And exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me personally?  The flurry of new-ness often has me feeling overwhelmed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wwdc---the-worldwide-developer-chase&#34;&gt;WWDC - The Worldwide Developer Chase&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes time for WWDC, are you like me?  Do you conjure up a mental image of a race?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s as if all of us who are enrolled in the Apple Developer Program line up at the starting line and wait for the pistol to fire, signaling the sprint that is the Worldwide Developer &lt;del&gt;Conference&lt;/del&gt; Chase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The race metaphor induces pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pressure to figure things out as quickly as you can.&lt;br&gt;
Pressure to be one of the rist to download Xcode {next}.&lt;br&gt;
Pressure to install the new beta operating systems.&lt;br&gt;
Pressure to master the new APIs and features of Apple&amp;rsquo;s platforms.
Pressure to make a discovery, publish it out, and get noticed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, it can be discouraging to watch the Twitter feeds of others who seem to be &lt;strong&gt;much faster&lt;/strong&gt; than me at all of those things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watch the race to &amp;ldquo;be first&amp;rdquo; go on around me and realize:  I can&amp;rsquo;t compete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But&amp;hellip; Why?  Why do this to ourselves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wwdc---the-worldwide-developer-community&#34;&gt;WWDC - The Worldwide Developer Community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if we could shift the thinking?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you build apps because it&amp;rsquo;s something you love to do, here&amp;rsquo;s what I propose:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nix the race metaphor&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If writing Swift is something you enjoy because it&amp;rsquo;s fulfilling in itself, there&amp;rsquo;s no need to worry about how fast you&amp;rsquo;re able to grasp all the new-ness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competitors are always going to be out there, always trying to one-up another.  That&amp;rsquo;s not the group of people I want to be a part of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, I gravitate to the global body of like-minded Swifters who, like me, enjoy building apps and contributing our share of bytes to the Internet in order to nudge the world in a positive direction.  Thankfully, there are &lt;strong&gt;plenty&lt;/strong&gt; of these kinds of folks out there to befriend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bottom line:&lt;/strong&gt; Take your time.  Enjoy yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Build that example Xcode project and publish it to GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tweet that new discovery that someone else already discovered and tweeted about before you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write that blog post without worrying with how much attention you garner from others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s okay!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do what you do because you love it.  I guarantee it will impact &lt;em&gt;somebody&lt;/em&gt;.  &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/andrewcbancroft&#34;&gt;@me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d&lt;/em&gt; love to hear what you&amp;rsquo;re discovering!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WWDC isn&amp;rsquo;t a Worldwide Developer &lt;strong&gt;Competition&lt;/strong&gt; when you&amp;rsquo;re contributing to the Worldwide Developer &lt;strong&gt;Community&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>