<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pluralsights on Andrew Bancroft</title>
    <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/pluralsight/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pluralsights on Andrew Bancroft</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 10:03:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/pluralsight/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>iOS Data Persistence: The Big Picture</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/pluralsight/2019-04-30-ios-data-persistence-the-big-picture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 10:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/pluralsight/2019-04-30-ios-data-persistence-the-big-picture/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve all been there. Do a search on the topic of &amp;ldquo;saving data in iOS&amp;#8221; and you&amp;rsquo;ll get dozens of search results mentioning at least six different frameworks and platforms, and a month’s worth of reading.
Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be nice to distill the possibilities down into just what you need in order to start down a path for persisting data in your app?
&amp;ldquo;iOS Data Persistence: The Big Picture&amp;#8221; will be worth the hour of your time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CloudKit Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/pluralsight/2018-09-24-cloudkit-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 17:58:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/pluralsight/2018-09-24-cloudkit-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>At the core of developing a seamless and collaborative data sharing experience for Apple’s platforms is a thorough knowledge of CloudKit.
In this course, you’ll learn to leverage Apple’s flagship framework to achieve your app’s remote data storage and data sharing requirements.
First, you’ll learn how to configure CloudKit in your Xcode project and how to save, query, update, and delete data that your users store in iCloud.
Next, you’ll explore how to synchronize data across a user’s devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Core Data Fundamentals with Swift</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/pluralsight/2017-04-02-core-data-fundamentals-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 22:04:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/pluralsight/2017-04-02-core-data-fundamentals-swift/</guid>
      <description>Core Data is an extremely powerful framework for managing and persisting data on your users&amp;rsquo; devices. And let&amp;rsquo;s face it: saving data to your users&amp;rsquo; devices is inevitable. The question is, which data management and persistence technology you use when the time comes for you to tackle this challenge?
&amp;ldquo;Core Data Fundamentals with Swift&amp;rdquo; will give you the essential skills you need to architect an app to use Core Data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Xcode Project Dependencies with CocoaPods</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/pluralsight/2016-02-03-managing-xcode-project-dependencies-with-cocoapods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 18:23:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/pluralsight/2016-02-03-managing-xcode-project-dependencies-with-cocoapods/</guid>
      <description>Course Outline I try to get as practical as possible in the course. As you&amp;rsquo;re watching you&amp;rsquo;ll be &amp;ldquo;embedded&amp;#8221; into a team of iOS developers, and you&amp;rsquo;ll explore the problems that CocoaPods can solve for you by watching the team struggle through not having a dependency manager, and then sharing in their victories as they bring in CocoaPods to ease that dependency management struggle.
The course is a progressive journey.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>