<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journey in iOS Development Series on Andrew Bancroft</title>
    <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/tags/journey-in-ios-development-series/</link>
    <description>Recent content about iOS development with Swift in Journey in iOS Development Series  from Andrew Bancroft.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 19:51:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/tags/journey-in-ios-development-series/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Journey in iOS Development Series – In the Beginning…</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2013/03/16/learning-ios-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 19:51:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2013/03/16/learning-ios-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m starting a series related to my journey in learning to develop iOS apps. As lightbulbs come on for me, I plan to write up what I&amp;rsquo;m learning, if nothing else for my own reference. But I do hope my readers enjoy the discoveries I make along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These first few blogs will be somewhat autobiographical, so hopefully I don&amp;rsquo;t bore you to death. I&amp;rsquo;ll try and make them quick. More technical stuff will appear very soon. I thought to write a short article about how I got started. If I had an &amp;ldquo;In the beginning…” moment, what would that be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-early-days&#34;&gt;The Early Days&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems like just yesterday I was a little boy visiting my Grandpa&amp;rsquo;s house in Lawton, OK, eager to play on Grandpa&amp;rsquo;s computer. Computers in the early 90&amp;rsquo;s were still not quite the commodity they are in 2013. We didn&amp;rsquo;t own one yet, but &lt;em&gt;Grandpa&lt;/em&gt; did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I had to point to an &amp;ldquo;In the beginning…” stage, it&amp;rsquo;d be the times when Grandpa sat down with me and taught me about computers. Not just games (although I did enjoy Submarine and Wheel of Fortune for DOS a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt;) – he taught me the basics of how to instruct a computer.  He taught me to program. He was a Master of DOS and a QBasic Guru. If I had to guess, he still prefers elements of both today. :]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is, quite simply, an amazing man. He is now a retired entrepreneur, but when he was running his music store there were always those &amp;ldquo;things that needed to be done”.  He viewed the &amp;ldquo;gotta do it&amp;rsquo;s” as an opportunity to automate by programming a computer to do it &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; __him, rather than do it by hand. He&amp;rsquo;s showed me how he programmed apps to produce his financial statements, track his budget, print invoices, and all kinds of other &amp;ldquo;by hand” stuff that he was able to make &amp;ldquo;automagically” with a computer. It was (and still is) fascinating to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to those early years of influence, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from Grandpa that even though &amp;ldquo;there&amp;rsquo;s an app for that” already, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean it&amp;rsquo;ll work for you how you want it to work. Grandpa could be happy with 99% of an app&amp;rsquo;s functionality, but there&amp;rsquo;d always be that &lt;em&gt;one thing&lt;/em&gt; that bugged him. What did he do? He wrote his own. He made it work how &lt;em&gt;he&lt;/em&gt; wanted it to work. He may not have been inventing a new wheel every time, but because he could program, he could improve the existing wheel to his liking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this has served to motivate me in my pursuit of programming in general.  I love my Grandpa.  My Grandpa loves computers.  The little kid inside of me is yelling, &amp;ldquo;Me too!  Me too!” to this day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Grandpa just turned 81 and he still loves the computing world.  It&amp;rsquo;s been great fun to watch him use his latest computer: his iPhone.  It&amp;rsquo;s been even &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; fun to show him the little apps I&amp;rsquo;m making as I learn to program for iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up will be a post on how I&amp;rsquo;ve approached learning to program for iOS.  What&amp;rsquo;s my strategy and how is it going so far?  See you again soon with all that and more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>