<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Storyboard on Andrew Bancroft</title>
    <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/tags/storyboard/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Storyboard on Andrew Bancroft</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 18:20:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/tags/storyboard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Buttons to the Navigation Bar with Storyboards</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/blog/ios-development/ui-work/adding-buttons-to-the-navigation-bar-with-storyboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 18:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/blog/ios-development/ui-work/adding-buttons-to-the-navigation-bar-with-storyboards/</guid>
      <description>Updated on March 20, 2017 – Xcode 8 &amp;amp; Swift 3
If you&amp;rsquo;re having trouble figuring out how to add buttons to the navigation bar in your Storyboard-based iOS app, my goal in this article is to help you through the process. Knowing what to click and where to drag to get things wired up isn&amp;rsquo;t entirely intuitive, so I want to be of help if I can.
Lots of StackOverflow posts point us to just adding the buttons in code, but for those who lean toward trying to do as much in the Storyboard designer as possible, this approach feels out of place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular Progress Indicator in Swift</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/blog/ios-development/swift-how-tos/circular-progress-indicator-in-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 04:31:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/blog/ios-development/swift-how-tos/circular-progress-indicator-in-swift/</guid>
      <description>Updated on April 17, 2017 – Swift 3
Circular progress indicators are a nice and compact way to visualize progress information for users of your iOS app. I was extremely grateful to come across Kaan Dedeoglu&amp;rsquo;s KDCircularProgress project on GitHub. It&amp;rsquo;s a versatile little UI component written in Swift that provides a great amount of flexibility and customization options. I love it!
As a bonus to this amazing component, recent contributions by Kaan have opened up the ability for us to lay out and set up the circular progress indicator in the Storyboard!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>