<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Calendars on Andrew Bancroft</title>
    <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/tags/calendars/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Calendars on Andrew Bancroft</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 17:50:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/tags/calendars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Listing Calendar Events with Event Kit and Swift</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2016/04/28/listing-calendar-events-with-event-kit-and-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 17:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2016/04/28/listing-calendar-events-with-event-kit-and-swift/</guid>
      <description>This is the continuation of a series of articles I&amp;#8217;ve writing for Swift developers working with Event Kit.
Supposing that after asking the user for permission to use their calendars, and even allowing users to create new calendars from within your iOS app, one possible next step could be to list out all of the events for a calendar that they tap on.
Jump to&amp;#8230;   Demo   Example project   Querying for events    Context: View controller   Configure start and end dates   Use the event store to generate NSPredicate   Query the event store with generated NSPredicate</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Calendars with Event Kit and Swift</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2015/06/17/creating-calendars-with-event-kit-and-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 17:46:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2015/06/17/creating-calendars-with-event-kit-and-swift/</guid>
      <description>Updated on April 19, 2016 – Swift 2.1 | Added example project
Apple’s Event Kit framework empowers developers to interact with an iOS device’s calendar database. Not only can we read calendars and events from the database, we can also create calendars.
In a previous article, we looked at how to handle asking the user for permission to access their calendars. Now my goal is to show you how to create local calendars on the user&amp;#8217;s device programmatically with Swift using the Event Kit framework.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>