<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cocoapods on Andrew Bancroft</title>
    <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/tags/cocoapods/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cocoapods on Andrew Bancroft</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 18:23:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/tags/cocoapods/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Xcode Project Dependencies with CocoaPods</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/pluralsight/2016-02-03-managing-xcode-project-dependencies-with-cocoapods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 18:23:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/pluralsight/2016-02-03-managing-xcode-project-dependencies-with-cocoapods/</guid>
      <description>Course Outline I try to get as practical as possible in the course. As you&amp;rsquo;re watching you&amp;rsquo;ll be &amp;ldquo;embedded&amp;#8221; into a team of iOS developers, and you&amp;rsquo;ll explore the problems that CocoaPods can solve for you by watching the team struggle through not having a dependency manager, and then sharing in their victories as they bring in CocoaPods to ease that dependency management struggle.
The course is a progressive journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Considerations for Choosing 3rd Party Swift Libraries</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/blog/ios-development/dependency-management/considerations-for-choosing-3rd-party-swift-libraries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 18:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/blog/ios-development/dependency-management/considerations-for-choosing-3rd-party-swift-libraries/</guid>
      <description>While relying on 3rd party dependencies can provide you the benefit of not having to spend time implementing a portion of your app, realize that you’re essentially giving away little pieces of your app when you bring in a dependency.
You’re delegating away a certain level of control off to someone else who has no knowledge of or interest in the final outcome of your team’s app.
Adding dependencies to your project doesn’t come without cost, so it’s best to count that cost up front in order to make sure it’s a good idea to pursue this option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenSSL for iOS &amp; Swift the Easy Way</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/blog/ios-development/iap/openssl-for-ios-swift-the-easy-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 04:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/blog/ios-development/iap/openssl-for-ios-swift-the-easy-way/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on outfitting an app I&amp;rsquo;m working on to be able to validate receipts to verify purchases of the app.
Little did I know, this adventure would introduce the need to understand how to use cryptography in order to work with the receipt.

Cryptography library needed In order to even &amp;ldquo;open&amp;#8221; the receipt itself, we&amp;rsquo;ve got to work with something called a &amp;ldquo;PKCS #7 container&amp;#8221;. Once we get the container open, we need to be able to validate Apple&amp;rsquo;s certificate that they use to sign every purchase of every app.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>