<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CloudKit on Andrew Bancroft</title>
    <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/tags/cloudkit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CloudKit on Andrew Bancroft</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 10:03:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/tags/cloudkit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>iOS Data Persistence: The Big Picture</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/pluralsight/2019-04-30-ios-data-persistence-the-big-picture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 10:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/pluralsight/2019-04-30-ios-data-persistence-the-big-picture/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve all been there. Do a search on the topic of &amp;ldquo;saving data in iOS&amp;#8221; and you&amp;rsquo;ll get dozens of search results mentioning at least six different frameworks and platforms, and a month’s worth of reading.
Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be nice to distill the possibilities down into just what you need in order to start down a path for persisting data in your app?
&amp;ldquo;iOS Data Persistence: The Big Picture&amp;#8221; will be worth the hour of your time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CloudKit Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/pluralsight/2018-09-24-cloudkit-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 17:58:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/pluralsight/2018-09-24-cloudkit-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>At the core of developing a seamless and collaborative data sharing experience for Apple’s platforms is a thorough knowledge of CloudKit.
In this course, you’ll learn to leverage Apple’s flagship framework to achieve your app’s remote data storage and data sharing requirements.
First, you’ll learn how to configure CloudKit in your Xcode project and how to save, query, update, and delete data that your users store in iCloud.
Next, you’ll explore how to synchronize data across a user’s devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Case for CloudKit</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/blog/ios-development/data-persistence/case-for-cloudkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 11:58:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/blog/ios-development/data-persistence/case-for-cloudkit/</guid>
      <description>When it comes to remote backend services for mobile apps, you’ve got options. What&amp;rsquo;s the case for CloudKit? Where does Apple&amp;rsquo;s remote data storage and sharing solution fit into the Apple Developer&amp;rsquo;s toolbox?
I recently put out a survey on Twitter, just to get a feel for what folks are using.#iosdev folks: When your app needs a backend (ie, a remote server / remote database), what do you use?  I’m also interested in the “why” – reply with a tweet if you care to share!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>