<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Focus on Andrew Bancroft</title>
    <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/tags/focus/</link>
    <description>Recent content about iOS development with Swift in Focus  from Andrew Bancroft.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:04:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/tags/focus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Effective Ways to Keep You Focused as a Creator</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2017/04/20/3-effective-ways-to-keep-you-focused-as-a-creator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 18:04:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2017/04/20/3-effective-ways-to-keep-you-focused-as-a-creator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;away-with-the-phone&#34;&gt;Away with the Phone!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put your phone away. Far away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not in your pocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not on your desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In a drawer&lt;/strong&gt; – &lt;em&gt;away&lt;/em&gt; from you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disconnect&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should be able to tell if you&amp;rsquo;ve got an emergency call coming in, but past that, aim to be completely oblivious to every other kind of notification flowing into your smart device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you use a time management technique like &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pomodoro_Technique&#34;&gt;Pomodoro&lt;/a&gt; (there are plenty of timers and apps in the app store to keep you on track with this strategy), you get 5 minutes every half hour to pause from making awesome stuff. Use &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; time to get up, stretch, and, if you must, check your phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able to easily reach my phone is a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt;, huge productivity killer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started putting it in a drawer with the ringer on at a reasonable volume level so as not to miss an emergency. Life has been much more productive since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;music-to-code-by&#34;&gt;Music to Code By&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting your phone away minimizes physical distractions from your environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mtcb.pwop.com/&#34;&gt;Music to Code By&lt;/a&gt; minimizes &lt;em&gt;mental&lt;/em&gt; distractions and keeps you focused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be mislead by the title. It&amp;rsquo;s not just for programmers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need to write, organize, or just &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; in general, I highly recommend this invaluable resource.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem I always have with music when it comes to productivity is that…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The music has words and I wanna sing! (sorry, teammates)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The music is too mellow and causes me to want to sleep.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The music is too up-beat or interesting… interesting enough to distract me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mtcb.pwop.com/&#34;&gt;Music to Code By&lt;/a&gt; is literally the Goldilocks of music for concentration purposes. No words. Not too slow. Not too fast or &amp;ldquo;interesting”. &lt;strong&gt;Just right&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought the &lt;a href=&#34;https://secure.pwop.com/music-to-code-by-download-only&#34;&gt;original 3 tracks&lt;/a&gt;, and it&amp;rsquo;s been the best $18 I&amp;rsquo;ve spent to improve my focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking: I have to spend money??!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, you&amp;rsquo;d spend money to buy a hammer or a saw if you needed to build something, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;d drop a few dollars on an app if you knew it&amp;rsquo;d be worth it for the job you needed it to do, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of Music to Code By as a tool for your brain&amp;rsquo;s focus… a &amp;ldquo;clamp” if you will, to keep you riveted on what you need to accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can&amp;rsquo;t afford $20 right now, can you afford $10? Save for two months and &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; buy it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t encountered any other tool apart from these sound tracks that I can spend dollars on that keeps me focused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full disclosure: No one paid me to say all that. I&amp;rsquo;ve really just been &lt;em&gt;that impacted&lt;/em&gt; by the product that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t keep from commending it to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;keep-a-text-editor-window-open-but-minimized&#34;&gt;Keep a Text Editor Window Open (but minimized)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever a distracting thought comes to mind, open the text editor and jot down the thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh! I&amp;rsquo;ve got to remember to call ___”…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Text editor window –&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve got to call ___” –&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimize –&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Back to making great things!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Blog post idea!”…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Text editor window –&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type &amp;ldquo;[Blog post idea]” –&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimize –&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continue that awesome project!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always have a text editor window open and ready to record &lt;em&gt;whatever&lt;/em&gt; your random ramblings may be. Your mind can effectively &amp;ldquo;let go” because you just preserved what it alerted you to in the text file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t keep the window on the screen all the time though. You&amp;rsquo;ll be tempted to glance over at it too often. Jot down the thought and then minimize it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh. And be sure to &lt;em&gt;save&lt;/em&gt; the file. :]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-do-_you_-do&#34;&gt;What do &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; do?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are my top three right now. What do &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; do to keep focused on what matters?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sound off in the comments – I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear your productivity hacks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>