<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Event Kit on Andrew Bancroft</title>
    <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/tags/event-kit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Event Kit on Andrew Bancroft</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 17:37:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/tags/event-kit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Calendar Events with Event Kit and Swift</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/blog/ios-development/eventkit/creating-calendar-events-with-event-kit-and-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 17:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/blog/ios-development/eventkit/creating-calendar-events-with-event-kit-and-swift/</guid>
      <description>Folks have asked more about working with Event Kit and Swift, so the series continues with this guide on how to create calendar events with Event Kit and Swift!
Previous guides in the series include the following:
Previous Guides    Beginner’s Guide to Event Kit in Swift – Requesting Permission    Creating Calendars with Event Kit and Swift    Listing Calendar Events with Event Kit and Swift</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Calendars with Event Kit and Swift</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/blog/ios-development/eventkit/creating-calendars-with-event-kit-and-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 17:46:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/blog/ios-development/eventkit/creating-calendars-with-event-kit-and-swift/</guid>
      <description>Updated on April 19, 2016 – Swift 2.1 | Added example project
Apple’s Event Kit framework empowers developers to interact with an iOS device’s calendar database. Not only can we read calendars and events from the database, we can also create calendars.
In a previous article, we looked at how to handle asking the user for permission to access their calendars. Now my goal is to show you how to create local calendars on the user&amp;rsquo;s device programmatically with Swift using the Event Kit framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginner’s Guide to Event Kit in Swift – Requesting Permission</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/blog/ios-development/eventkit/beginners-guide-to-eventkit-in-swift-requesting-permission/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 20:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/blog/ios-development/eventkit/beginners-guide-to-eventkit-in-swift-requesting-permission/</guid>
      <description>Updated on October 26, 2016 – Swift 3.0
EventKit provides a set of classes for accessing and manipulating a user&amp;rsquo;s calendar events and reminders. In the tutorial that follows, my goal is to walk you through the first steps of setting up an app that utilizes EventKit. I will demonstrate how to request permission to the user&amp;rsquo;s calendar and show a couple of examples for how to handle the user&amp;rsquo;s response (for when they grant access, or deny it).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>