<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reporting Services on Andrew Bancroft</title>
    <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/categories/reporting-services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reporting Services on Andrew Bancroft</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 13:56:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/categories/reporting-services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SSRS: Which server sent my e-mail subscription?</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2012/07/25/ssrs-which-server-sent-my-e-mail-subscription/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 13:56:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2012/07/25/ssrs-which-server-sent-my-e-mail-subscription/</guid>
      <description>I was recently troubleshooting a seemingly bizarre issue I was having with one of our report subscriptions – the production version was running normally, but our customer suddenly began receiving a very old version of the same report subscription. After disabling the subscription from all non-production servers that I knew about, the customer continued to receive the rogue e-mail. I needed to figure out which “mystery” report server was sending the e-mail subscription.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting SQL Server 2012 Reporting Services and SharePoint 2010 Integration (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2012/06/30/troubleshooting-sql-server-2012-reporting-services-and-sharepoint-2010-integration-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 19:44:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2012/06/30/troubleshooting-sql-server-2012-reporting-services-and-sharepoint-2010-integration-part-2/</guid>
      <description>You can visit Part 1 of this troubleshooting series by clicking here.
During our configuration of Reporting Services for SharePoint I ran into another common issue.
I consulted MSDN once again and followed the directions given at this MSDN article. Even after following all these instructions, when I would attempt to create a new BI Semantic Model Connection in the SharePoint library, I would receive the following error:
Cannot connect to the server or database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting SQL Server 2012 Reporting Services and SharePoint 2010 Integration (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2012/06/30/troubleshooting-sql-server-2012-reporting-services-and-sharepoint-2010-integration-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 19:06:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2012/06/30/troubleshooting-sql-server-2012-reporting-services-and-sharepoint-2010-integration-part-1/</guid>
      <description>I recently worked with our SharePoint administrator to install SQL Server 2012 Reporting Services in SharePoint Integrated Mode to take advantage of PowerView. By following the installation instructions found at this MSDN article, we were able to painlessly install both Reporting Services and the Reporting Services Add-in from the SQL Server installation media.
Then began the configuration process. Since everyone&amp;#8217;s environment is different, I found it difficult to troubleshoot some of the odd behavior that we were running in to.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>