<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reporting Services on Andrew Bancroft</title>
    <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/tags/reporting-services/</link>
    <description>Recent content about iOS development with Swift in Reporting Services  from Andrew Bancroft.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 19:44:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/tags/reporting-services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting SQL Server 2012 Reporting Services and SharePoint 2010 Integration (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2012/06/30/troubleshooting-sql-server-2012-reporting-services-and-sharepoint-2010-integration-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 19:44:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2012/06/30/troubleshooting-sql-server-2012-reporting-services-and-sharepoint-2010-integration-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can visit Part 1 of this troubleshooting series by &lt;a href=&#34;http://andrewcbancroft.com/2012/06/30/troubleshooting-sql-server-2012-reporting-services-and-sharepoint-2010-integration-part-1/&#34; title=&#34;Troubleshooting SQL Server 2012 Reporting Services and SharePoint 2010 Integration (Part 1)&#34;&gt;clicking here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During our configuration of Reporting Services for SharePoint I ran into another common issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I consulted MSDN once again and followed the directions &lt;a title=&#34;PowerPivot BI Semantic Model Connection (.bism) &#34; href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/gg471575.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;given at this MSDN article&lt;/a&gt;.  Even after following all these instructions, when I would attempt to create a new BI Semantic Model Connection in the SharePoint library, I would receive the following error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
  Cannot connect to the server or database.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even after adding the Reporting Services service account to the SSAS Tabular instance as a server administrator, we still hit this error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again I found little documentation out there as I was troubleshooting, presumably because SQL Server 2012 is still quite new.  Here&amp;rsquo;s what we did to fix our problem:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;The Analysis Services service must be running under a domain account.&lt;/strong&gt;  When I installed SSAS, I took all the defaults for the server installation.  The SSAS service was running under some default built-in account which ended up being the problem.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we switched this to run under a domain account, I was able to create BI Semantic Model Connections using this library document type with no issues.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting SQL Server 2012 Reporting Services and SharePoint 2010 Integration (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2012/06/30/troubleshooting-sql-server-2012-reporting-services-and-sharepoint-2010-integration-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 19:06:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2012/06/30/troubleshooting-sql-server-2012-reporting-services-and-sharepoint-2010-integration-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently worked with our SharePoint administrator to install SQL Server 2012 Reporting Services in SharePoint Integrated Mode to take advantage of PowerView.  By following the installation instructions &lt;a title=&#34;Install Reporting Services SharePoint Mode as a Single Server Farm&#34; href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/gg492276.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;found at this MSDN article&lt;/a&gt;, we were able to painlessly install both Reporting Services and the Reporting Services Add-in from the SQL Server installation media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then began the configuration process.  Since everyone&amp;rsquo;s environment is different, I found it difficult to troubleshoot some of the odd behavior that we were running in to.  In Part 1 of this post I want to focus on what we did to overcome a specific error we were receiving:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After installation, I created a Business Intelligence Center site without any trouble.  In the Connections library, I would attempt to add a Report Data Source and receive a SharePoint page that detailed the following error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    This SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS) functionality is not supported.  Use Central Administration to verify and fix one or more of the following issues:
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      A report server URL is not configured.  Use the SSRS Integration page to set it.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      The SSRS service application proxy is not configured.  Use the SSRS service application pages to configure the proxy.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      The SSRS service application is not mapped to this web application.  Use the SSRS service application pages to associate the SSRS service application proxy to the web application.
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other times, I would receive a little bit more of a generic message saying something to the effect of &amp;ldquo;This SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS) functionality is not supported” or &amp;ldquo;Unsupported Reporting Services Functionality”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, our specific problem was unrelated to any three of those bullet points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our solution?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
  Make sure to install the &#34;Reporting Services Add-in for SharePoint Products&amp;#8221; to all Web Front-End (WFE) nodes of your SharePoint farm.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Feature Selection screen of SQL Server setup, you can simply choose &amp;ldquo;Reporting Services Add-in for SharePoint Products” on your other WFE nodes.  You don&amp;rsquo;t need to install the Database Engine Services or Reporting Services – SharePoint all over again…just the Add-in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We began to suspect it was something related to missing components on the other nodes because as I was troubleshooting, I noticed that if I attempted to create a Report Data Source enough times, I would be able to proceed to different stages of the creation process.  Sometimes I would hit the error right away.  Sometimes I would get to the page where I could fill out the connection details but when I would attempt to save the data source I would get one of the error pages described above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we installed the Reporting Services Add-in on all WFE nodes, the problem stopped and we have not experienced any difficulty since.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>