<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software Development on Andrew Bancroft</title>
    <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/categories/software-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software Development on Andrew Bancroft</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 18:40:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/categories/software-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix MAMP, MySQL Workbench “Failed to Connect to MySQL”</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2015/01/19/fix-mamp-mysql-workbench-failed-connect-mysql/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 18:40:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2015/01/19/fix-mamp-mysql-workbench-failed-connect-mysql/</guid>
      <description>Installing MAMP was easy. I did, however, spend at least 45 minutes trying to get MySQL Workbench to connect to my local MySQL database server. The solution was simple, but getting there led me around the Internet and back with little help. Hopefully this signpost will help others having connection issues with MySQL Workbench to MAMP MySQL servers as well.
Once MAMP is installed and the MySQL server has started, you&amp;#8217;ll be taken to a start screen that looks something like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distinguishing Between Multiple UIActionSheets with Swift</title>
      <link>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2014/11/16/distinguishing-between-multiple-uiactionsheets-with-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 04:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.andrewcbancroft.com/2014/11/16/distinguishing-between-multiple-uiactionsheets-with-swift/</guid>
      <description>The challenge when dealing with the presentation and handling of more than one UIActionSheet in a single View Controller is made clear by asking, &amp;#8220;How am I going to tell which action sheet I&amp;#8217;m dealing with so that I can handle the user&amp;#8217;s choice appropriately?&amp;#8221;
Presumably, the user&amp;#8217;s interaction with one of the action sheets will be different than the other(s), so you&amp;#8217;ll need to think through how to distinguish between them, in order to respond to that interaction appropriately.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>